Princeton Ethiopic Manuscripts, late 1600s-1900s: Finding Aid C0776
Manuscripts Division
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 56: A Book of Magical Prayers With Talismanic Drawings, early 19th century; Manuscript on vellum, 35 leaves, mostly in gatherings of 8, many of the leaves are stained and rubbed, and the text is at times difficult to read. 2 columns, 16-20 lines in different hands
  Illustration: Fol. 35r: Virgin and Child.
  This is a high-quality magical prayer book made in the first half of the nineteenth century likely for a member of the nobility. As expected, there is no formal indication of date. The several hands are all a 19th century räqiq hand, of varying quality, certain features of which might suggest a date earlier rather than a later in the century, and the costume worn by the figure of the supplicant in the drawing on fol. 33v resembles that worn by the nobility up to the 1850s.
  There are numerous talismanic drawings and the quality of many of them shows greater finesse than is usual in magical manuscripts of this sort. This type of manuscript, intended for practical use by a däbtära as a source book for the composition of amulet scrolls or kitab, would normally be copied by the original owner himself, but as is the case here could also be passed on to others.
  The text comprises a collection of prayers for various purposes. In the present manuscript these are predominantly prayers against drowning (s'älot bä'entä mäst'em) and prayers to counteract spells (mäftehé seray), though there is also a version of the well known magical prayer known as the Säyfä Esat or Sword of Fire. The accompanying diagrams are intended as prophylactic designs for incorporation in amulets, and the charts or tables either as devices for divination or schematic representations of protective processes. The prayer texts themselves typically comprise lists of magical names (asmat) for the summoning of power or the protection and shielding of the individual from demonic forces.
  The name of the original owner and probable scribe has been erased throughout, though the first element of his name, Wäldä..., is still occasionally visible.
  - A Composite Text Beginning in Abrupto With an Extract from the Gospel Text Recounting Jesus' Recruiting of the Apostle Andrew, Followed by a Magical Prayer or Prayers Invoking the Same Apostle, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 1r-3v. (Unitid 56)
  - A Prayer for the Binding of Demons, Barya and Zar, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 4v-5r. (Unitid 56)
    In red, with a small haräg at the beginning and a talismanic figure in the form of an eight-pointed star with serpents' head arms at the end.
  - Series of Prayers for the Undoing of Spells or Charms, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 9v-13v. (Unitid 56)
    Incorporating 5 talismanic drawings or charts, one [f.10v] of nine squares with a face in the centre square and cherubim in each of the four corner squares, another [f.12v] in grid form possibly representing the "net of Solomon" for trapping spirits. The motif of alternating faces in a grid-pattern design also appears in the drawing at the end of the group of prayers [f.13v].
  - Series of Prayers for the Undoing of Spells, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 14r-17r. (Unitid 56)
    Incorporating another grid-like talismanic drawing [f.18r] and two smaller designs.
  - Series of Prayers for "Drowning" [of Demons], early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 17r-20r. (Unitid 56)
    Incorporating 5 small talismanic drawings.
  - Series of Prayers for the Undoing of Spells, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 20r. (Unitid 56)
    Incorporating talismanic drawings and grid-patterns.
  - Series of Prayers for the Undoing of Spells, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 20r-29v. (Unitid 56)
  - An Extensive Prayer Without a Title But Also for Release from Spells and Charms, early 19th century; 1 item Located on folio 29v-32v. (Unitid 56)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 57: Miracles of Mary With Three Miracles of Saint George, mid 18th century; Mostly in numbered gatherings of 8 leaves, the manuscript is in excellent condition and shows no damage and only a little natural wear to the edges of some leaves, 1 col. of 15 lines, written in black with the usual rubrics (alternate opening lines of sections, the name of Mary and Saint George as well as those of the owners, major punctuation) in a generally well-formed early räqiq hand [4-5mm], deteriorating somewhat towards the end of the text, datable to the first half or middle of the eighteenth century, many of the miracle texts are marked with small coloured threads sewn on to the edge of the leaves, ruling and pricking visible throughout, there are 49 full page miniatures, 6 half page miniatures; bound between wooden boards covered and with a spine in tooled leather, brocade insert panels on the inside of the covers. Fols. 1v-3r, 4v, 15v, 22v, 35v, 48v, 82v, 95v, 112v, 116v, 143r, 163r, 164-165: blank. (Unitid 57)
  The paintings are high quality examples painted in the Second Gondarene style, which is associated with the patronage of Empress Mentewwab and her son, Iyasu II (r. 1730-55), though it continued in use later into the eighteenth century. The paintings are mostly framed within a double red border and include descriptive text in red or black, either directly on the painting or in the top or bottom margins.
  Illustration: Fol. 3v: Painting 1: St. George and the dragon.
  Illustration: Fol. 4r: Painting 2: Virgin and Child with the archangels Michael and Gabriel; below is the prostrate figure of a supplicant, named as Awsabyos.
  Illustration: Fol. 12r: Painting 3: The Virgin Mary presents a robe and a throne to Däqseyos.
  Illustration: Fol. 12v: Painting 4: The archangel Michael strikes down the bishop who sat on Däqseyos' throne.
  Illustration: Fol. 15r: Painting 5: The Virgin Mary gives food and clothes to the monk.
  Illustration: Fol. 18v: Painting 6: The Virgin blesses the artisan.
  Illustration: Fol. 22r: Painting 7: The Virgin revives the Jew of Akhmim.
  Illustration: Fol. 25v: Painting 8: Demyanos writing the Miracles of Mary.
  Illustration: Fol. 26r: Painting 9: The Virgin shows Demyanos the pillar of gold in heaven.
  Illustration: Fol. 29v: Painting 10: Abbas cuts off his hand.
  Illustration: Fol. 30r: Painting 11: The Virgin restores Abbas' hand.
  Illustration: Fol. 35r: Painting 12: The Virgin appears to Isaac and raises him up.
  Illustration: Fol. 39v: Painting 13: The Virgin makes the girl follow her.
  Illustration: Fol. 40r: Painting 14: The girl receives communion.
  Illustration: Fol. 44v: Painting 15: [left] The artist falls, dragged down by a demon; [right] the Virgin raises him up.
  Illustration: Fol. 47v: Painting 16: The Virgin brings the sick man to Jerusalem (he is shown being baptized in the Jordan).
  Illustration: Fol. 48r: Painting 17: A rectangular: building or church representing Jerusalem.
  Illustration: Fol. 54v: Painting 18: Zäkaryas crowns the Virgin with roses.
  Illustration: Fol. 55r: Painting 19: Zäkaryas is rescued from the thieves.
  Illustration: Fol. 58v: Painting 20: The thief's teeth shatter when he tries to eat the bread he has stolen.
  Illustration: Fol. 59r: Painting 21: The repentant thieves do homage to the Virgin.
  Illustration: Fol. 63r: Painting 22: The two shipwrecked Arabs look on whilst their companion is swallowed by a whale.
  Illustration: Fol. 64v: Painting 23: The two surviving Arabs bring their gifts to the church.
  Illustration: Fol. 67r: Painting 24: The Virgin appears in a dream to the priest of the church.
  Illustration: Fol. 67v: Painting 25: The church appears by the sea shore.
  Illustration: Fol. 72r: Painting 26: The Virgin restores Yohannes' sight.
  Illustration: Fol. 76r: Painting 27: The merchant is struck in the eye by an arrow.
  Illustration: Fol. 76v: Painting 28: The Virgin restores the merchant's sight through an image of him.
  Illustration: Fol. 82r: Painting 29: The Virgin restores the girl's sight.
  Illustration: Fol. 87v: Painting 30: The Virgin appears in a dream to the widow and promises to look after her daughters.
  Illustration: Fol. 88r: Painting 31: Téwog takes the daughters to be married.
  Illustration: Fol. 91v: Painting 32: The two brothers writing.
  Illustration: Fol. 92r: Painting 33: The Virgin rescues the soul of the good brother.
  Illustration: Fol. 95r: Painting 34: The Virgin rescues George in the form of a dove.
  Illustration: Fol. 100r: Painting 35: The guardian of the church drives out Kät'ir.
  Illustration: Fol. 100v: Painting 36: The Virgin instructs the angels to punish the guardian.
  Illustration: Fol. 106v: Painting 37: St. George strikes down the dishonest merchant who had Näzib falsely accused.
  Illustration: Fol. 107r: Painting 38: Näzib brings his testimony before the judge.
  Illustration: Fol. 111v: Painting 39: The man praying in church.
  Illustration: Fol. 112r: Painting 40: The man shows his healed foot to the bishop.
  Illustration: Fol. 116r: Painting 41: The Virgin cures Märqoréwos of his leprosy.
  Illustration: Fol. 120v: Painting 42: The Virgin cures the woman of her lameness.
  Illustration: Fol. 129r: Painting 43: Sofya is delivered of her child by the angels.
  Illustration: Fol. 129v: Painting 44: The child, now grown, comes before the bishop.
  Illustration: Fol. 132v: Painting 45: Barok is attacked and killed by his enemies, and [right] his corpse is shown in the church.
  Illustration: Fol. 135r: Painting 46: The Virgin appears to Anest'asyos in a dream.
  Illustration: Fol. 138v: Painting 47: [left] The monk (called Sämalusi in the inscription) is attacked by his fellow monks, and [right] throws his cap to make a hole in the wall.
  Illustration: Fol. 143v: Painting 48: [top] The cannibal approaches the farmer; [bottom] he is shown eating his victims.
  Illustration: Fol. 144r: Painting 49: [top] His soul is saved by the Virgin after it has been weighed in the balance by the archangel Michael; [bottom] the cannibal gives water to the leper.
  Illustration: Fol. 146r: Painting 50: The widow prays to the Virgin Mary.
  Illustration: Fol. 146v: Painting 51: The Virgin comes to rescue the widow's son after he has been hanged.
  Illustration: Fol. 149v: Painting 52: The Virgin protects the woman and her child with her cloak.
  Illustration: Fol. 152v: Painting 53: The Virgin gives the dog water to drink from her shoe.
  Illustration: Fol. 155v: Painting 54: [top] Christ grants Mary the Covenant of Mercy; [below] a prostrate supplicant, identified as Awsabyos in the text below.
  Illustration: Fol. 163v: Painting 55: [top] The Trinity; [bottom] a prostrate supplicant, identified also as Awsabyos in spite of being clearly female.
  Date and provenance: Mid-18th century. There is no colophon giving the date of composition. However, the hand and style of the paintings are in keeping with a mid eighteenth century date. The invocations for blessings throughout the text are mostly made for one Lätes'un (m.) occasionally in conjunction with that Wälättä Täklä Haymanot (f.). However, the name Awsabyos (m.) has been inserted in the top margin of many leaves, and also appears alongside the picture of the prostrate supplicant in paintings 2, 54 and 55, though in the last instance the figure is clearly female.
  The text comprises 34 miracles of the Virgin Mary together with 3 miracles of St. George.
  Fol. 1r: Blank except for pen trial.
  Purchase, Sam Fogg, London.
  - Miracles of Mary, mid 18th century; Located on folio 5r-155r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Hildefonsus of Toledo [Däqseyos], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 5r-12r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Poor Monk Who Had Neither Food Nor Clothes, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 13r-14v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Artisan Who Was Devoted to the Virgin Mary, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 16r-18r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Jew of Akhmim, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 19r-21v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Damianus of Philippi [Demyanos of Felp'esyos], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 23r-25v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Pope Leon [Bishop Abbas of Romé], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 26v-29v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Isaac the Monk, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 30v-34v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Man from Defra Whose Daughter Was Transported to Paradise, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 36r-39r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Artist Who Fell from His Scaffolding, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 40v-44r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Sick Merchant, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 45r-47r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Young Man Zacharias [Zäkaryas], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 49r-54r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Juliana and Barbara [Yolyana and Bärbara], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 55v-58r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Three Arabs of Rif, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 59v-62v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Church that Was Transported to the Shores of the Sea of "Iyariko", mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 64r-66v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Blind Priest, Yohannes of Bäkänsi, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 66v-71v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Rich Merchant of Qwälasyes, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 72v-75v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Daughter of Abreham of Bedreman, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 77r-81v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Poor Widow and Her Daughters, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 83r-87r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Two Brother Scribes, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 88v-91r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of George the Younger, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 92v-94v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Priest Kät'ir of Elkus [sic], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 96r-99v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Dyer Näzib, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 101r-106r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Man With a Club Foot, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 107v-111v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Bishop Mercurius [Märqoréwos], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 113r-115v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Woman of Haarlem [Hartälom], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 117-120v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Abbess Sophia of Carmel [Sofya of Qärmélos], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 121r-129r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of Barok of Finqi, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 129v-132r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Deacon Anastasius [Anest'asyos], mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 133r-134v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Monk Salusi of the Monastery of Qälmon, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 135v-138r. (Unitid 57)
    - [bottom, Different hand] Short Hymn or Prayer, mid-1700s>, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 138r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Cannibal of Qemer, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 139r-142v. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Widow's Son Who Was a Thief, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 144v-146r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Woman Who Gave Birth in a Storm At Sea, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 146v-149r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Thirsty Dog, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 150r-152r. (Unitid 57)
    - The Story of the Five Sorrows Told by the Virgin to Her Son and His Granting of the Covenant of Mercy on Her Behalf, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 153r-155r. (Unitid 57)
    - [bottom, Different hand] Prayer to the Virgin Mary, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 155r. (Unitid 57)
  - Miracles of St. George, mid 18th century; 1 item Located on folio 156r-162v. (Unitid 57)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 58: Ethiopic Amulet, 1900s; 1 item In the form of a miniature book. Parchment leaves (2 flyleaves at front; 18 leaves in 3 quires), with trim dimensions of 3.5 x 2.5 cm. Original blind-tooled leather binding. 3.5 x 2.5 cm (Unitid 58)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 59: Ethiopic Folding Picture Book, circa 1870-1930; 1 item On parchment. Comprised of 10 panels measuring approximately 50 x 50 cm each, opening horizontally 50 x 50 cm (Unitid 59)
  The panels contain scenes of the life of Christ, with brief inscriptions in Ge'ez.
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 60: Collection of Astrological and Divinatory Treatises, circa 1850-1899; 1 column [fols. 1-8, 12-13, 17v-22], 2 columns [fols. 9-11, 14, 23-29], 20-22 lines. Parchment. Composite manuscript, various hands. Wooden boards covered in stamped leather. Fol. 22v: Blank. (Unitid 60)
  The eight paintings were all added later.
  Illustration: Fol. 15r: Painting 1: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Virgo (Sanbulā).
  Illustration: Fol. 15v: Painting 2: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Cancer (Sart'ān).
  Illustration: Fol. 16r: Painting 3: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Leo ('Asad).
  Illustration: Fol. 16v: Painting 4: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Sagittarius (Qaws).
  Illustration: Fol. 17r: Painting 5: Figure representing the zodiacal sign Libra (Mizān).
  Illustration: Fol. 21r: Painting 6: Eight-pointed star design with central face.
  Illustration: Fol. 22r: Painting 7: Nine round faces encircling two square faces.
  Illustration: Fol. 22r [bottom]: Painting 8: Two circles with central faces.
  Immediate Source of Acquisition
  Gift of Bruce Willsie, Class of 1986 (AM 2013-44).
  - Explanation of the Stars (Fekkārē Kawākebt), circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 1r-8v. (Unitid 60)
    An astrological treatise, in Ge'ez with sections in Amharic. Incomplete, terminates in abrupto.
  - Divinatory Interpretations of Signs and Prescriptions [different hand], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 9r-11v, 14rv. (Unitid 60)
    In Amharic. Terminates in abrupto.
  - [Different hand], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 12r-13v. (Unitid 60)
  - Prayers for Undoing Spells and against Various Ailments, With Talismanic Drawings [different hand], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 17v-18v. (Unitid 60)
  - Further Divinations and Prescriptions, circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 19rv. (Unitid 60)
  - Magic Words and Phrases and Signs, circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 20r. (Unitid 60)
  - Series of Prayers against Budā, Qu[ra]ññā, Bāryā, etc. and Various Ailments, circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 20v-22r. (Unitid 60)
  - Further Divinations and Prescriptions [different hand], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 23r-28r. (Unitid 60)
  - Prayer Titled "The Chariot of Elijah" (Saragallā 'Ēlyās) [different hand], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 28rv. (Unitid 60)
  - Beginning of a Text Titled "The Epistles of Shem, Abraham and Isaac" [different Hand, and outlined], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 28v. (Unitid 60)
  - Magical Prescriptions and Procedures [different Hand, in Amharic], circa 1850-1899; 1 item Located on folio 29rv. (Unitid 60)
- Princeton Ethiopic Manuscript No. 61: Homilies and Miracles of St. Michael, 1800s; 2 columns, 20-21 lines. Parchment. 20 Paintings (added later), 8 colored [harags] or ornamental headpieces. Wooden boards covered in stamped leather with brocade insert panels on the inside, hide slipcase. (Unitid 61)
  The paintings and [harags] are all added later, the former in some cases apparently over text. There are also several [harags] drawn in pencil but not colored in. The paintings have been executed in an archaizing style by an accomplished artist, probably in the latter part of the 20th century.
  Illustration: Fol. 1r: Painting 1: The Annunciation.
  Illustration: Fol. 1v: Painting 2: The Nativity of Jesus.
  Illustration: Fol. 2r: Painting 3: God the Father, the Son and the Holy Ghost crowning Mary.
  Illustration: Fol. 2v: Painting 4: The Baptism of Jesus by John.
  Illustration: Fol. 3r: Painting 5: Jesus fasting in the desert, tempted by the Devil.
  Illustration: Fol. 3v: Painting 6: Our Lady Mary and Elizabeth.
  Illustration: Fol. 4r: Painting 7: The Virgin Mary giving Daqseyos a throne and a cloak in return for his having written the Book of her Miracles (a scene drawn from the Miracles of Mary text).
  Illustration: Fol. 4v: Painting 8: St. Mark the Evangelist.
  Illustration: Fol. 32v: Painting 9: St. Gabriel saving the three children from the fiery furnace.
  Illustration: Fol. 58v: Painting 10: The Resurrection of Our Lord, with the figures of Adam and Eve.
  Illustration: Fol. 67r: Painting 11: Herod ordering the execution of James the brother of John.
  Illustration: Fol. 107v: Painting 12: Jesus raising the widow's son.
  Illustration: Fol. 130r: Painting 13: Jesus healing the blind man at Bethsaida.
  Illustration: Fol. 139v: Painting 14: St. George slaying the dragon.
  Illustration: Fol. 154v: Painting 15: Mary prostrating herself before Our Lord.
  Illustration: Fol. 162r: Painting 16: Jesus raising Lazarus.
  Illustration: Fol. 177r: Painting 17: The Crucifixion.
  Illustration: Fol. 183v: Painting 18: Joseph and Nicodemus placing Jesus in the tomb.
  Illustration: Fol. 184r: Painting 19: The Deposition from the Cross.
  Illustration: Fol. 184v: Painting 20: St. Michael the Archangel.
  Former owners: Walda 'Iyasus and Walatta Heywat, also Hāyla Mikā'ēl
  - History of St. Michael the Archangel (Zēnā ... Qeddus Mikā'ēl Liqa Malā'ekt), 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 5r-11v. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Hedār (Nov. 21) by Abbā Damātēwos of Alexandria, 1800s; Located on folio 12r-25v. (Unitid 61)
    - Prayers to St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 26r-28r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 28r-30r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Hedār, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 30r-32r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Tāhsās (Dec. 21), 1800s; Located on folio 33r-41r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 41r-43r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Tāhsās, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 43v-44r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of T'er (Jan. 20), 1800s; Located on folio 44v-56r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 56r-58r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of T'er, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 58r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Yakkātit (Feb. 19), 1800s; Located on folio 59r-63r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 63r-65r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Yakkātit, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 65r-67r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Maggābit (Mar. 21) by John Bishop of Antioch, 1800s; Located on folio 67v-86v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 87r-90r. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Maggābit, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 90r. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Miyāzyā (Apr. 20) by "the Orthodox" (Retu'a Haymānot), 1800s; Located on folio 90v-96r. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 96r-99v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Miyāzyā, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 100rv. (Unitid 61)
  - Homily of St. Michael for the 12th of Genbot (May 20) by John Bishop of Ethiopia, 1800s; Located on folio 101r-103v. (Unitid 61)
    - A Miracle of St. Michael, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 103v-106v. (Unitid 61)
    - Synaxarium Entry for the 12th of Genbot, 1800s; 1 item Located on folio 106v-107r. (Unitid 61)